<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on 23 Summer Study</title><link>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on 23 Summer Study</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Acknowledgement</title><link>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/acknowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/acknowledge/</guid><description>Acknowledgement # Eight weeks have flown by, and as our self-supervised learning seminar comes to an end, my heart is full.
I want to send a big &amp;rsquo;thank you&amp;rsquo; to all of you. Your questions, your intelligence, and your genuine curiosity made every meeting memorable. We dived deep into the world of self-supervised learning, but what I&amp;rsquo;ll cherish the most are the bonds we formed and the shared passion for the scientific world.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction # Main topics # Easy-to-understanding Introduction to and advances in some regions of deep learning (Self-supervised learning, meta learning, transfer learning, etc.) - determined by everyone in this seminar. Some practical topics like backbones, optimizers and data augmentations may also incorporated depend on progress. You can get # Knowledge about fundamental and advanced methodologies in machine learning.
A proof of your study experience: this website - Every contribution you make to this seminar will be recorded</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://niusj03.github.io/23summer/docs/schedule/</guid><description>Schedule # Date Main Topic Speaker Jun 21 An Introduction of Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning: Principles, Mechanisms, and Variants Wang Ma Jun 29 The Bridge: Transferable Feature towards Advanced Mechanism Zebing Yun Jul 5 Semi-Supervised Learning based on Pseudo-labeling Shengjie Niu Jul 13 The Self-Distillation Family in Self-Supervised Learning Lifan Lin, Yue Wu Jul 20 The Deep Metric Learning Family in Self-Supervised Learning Xinyao Li, Yiming Zhang, Shengqi Fang Jul 27 Driving Neural Networks: An Exploration of Optimizers in Deep Learning &amp;amp; Ramblings in Optimization Wang Ma Aug 3 The Canonical Correlation Analysis Family in Self-Supervised Learning Xunyi Jiang, Langtian Ma Aug 10 Masked Image Model in Self-Supervised Learning Family in Self-Supervised Learning Shengjie Niu Please click the topics directly for detailed information like online link, main contents and references.</description></item></channel></rss>